By the way by the way It was confirmed It was
Por cierto por cierto Se confirmó Se
confirmed an
confirmó
exclusive from Telesalseo today on Confi
exclusiva de telesalseo hoy en el confi
TV on Confi TV Carlota Prado denounces
TV en el confi TV Carlota Prado denuncia
Mediaset Big Brother and its
a mediaset gran hermano y sus
workers for failing to provide help in the face of
trabajadores por omisión de Socorro ante
her sexual abuse in the house okay And here we have
su abuso sexual en la casa vale Y aquí
the article well let's take
tenemos el artículo que bueno le echamos
a look at
un vistazo
the most controversial case on television in
el caso más polémico de la televisión en
Spain the sexual abuse that
España el abuso sexual que sufrió
Carlota Prado suffered on the reality show Big
Carlota Prado en el reality show gran
Brother in November 2017 could
hermano en noviembre del año 2017 podría
extend Beyond the sentence that
extenderse Más allá de la condena que la
justice has determined against José
justicia ha determinado contra José
María López the aggressor and Sepelintv
María López el agresor y sepelintv
Prado has filed a new complaint
Prado ha Interpuesto una nueva denuncia
now against Mediaset Spain the
ahora en contra de mediaset España la
aforementioned company responsible for Big
citada empresa responsable de gran
Brother and the workers who
hermano y los trabajadores que
were in the house in Guadalid de la
estuvieron en la casa de guadalid de la
Sierra on the night of the events El Confidencial
sierra la noche de autos el confidencial
has had access to the request that
ha tenido acceso al requerimiento que
Carlota has filed the Civil Guard
Carlota ha Interpuesto la guardia civil
in Coín Málaga on May 8 we
en coín Málaga el pasado 8 de mayo
were already saying this okay I don't know
esto ya lo estuvimos diciendo vale No sé
if I have it here
si tengo por aquí
well this news was given to us
el bueno esta noticia nos la dio en
exclusively by Francisco here for our
exclusiva Francisco aquí para nuestro
channel the day we talked about the
canal el día que hablamos de la de la
sentence I don't have it here at hand but
condena no lo tengo por aquí a mano pero
well basically
bueno básicamente
Carlota has a list okay
Carlota tiene una lista vale esa lista
She already published that list on her
ya la publicó ella en su cuenta de
Twitter account and on her social networks on several
Twitter y en sus redes en varias
occasions and basically
ocasiones y básicamente
with all the workers who were
con todos los trabajadores que estaban
on Big Brother that night
en gran hermano
if I'm not mistaken I'm speaking from memory I
si no me equivoco os hablo de memoria me
could be wrong I don't know if it says
puedo equivocar no sé si por aquí pondrá
the number of workers here I do
la cantidad de trabajadores
n't know if it says here it doesn't say it doesn't
no sé si por aquí pondrá no lo pone
say the number of workers but
no pone la cantidad de trabajadores pero
if I'm not mistaken it was approximately
si no me equivoco eran aproximadamente
30 workers okay new complaint
unos 30 trabajadores vale denuncia nueva
Goodbye Big Brother man let's see clearly
Adiós gran hermano hombre a ver claro es
you realize that in order for you to report
que Tú date cuenta que para tu denunciar
Socorro's omission there has to be
la omisión de Socorro tiene que haber
a conviction of the abuse yes it's true
una condena del abuso sí que es verdad
that this has gone on for a long time
que esto se ha alargado mucho
and I personally would say that it's
y yo personalmente diría que está
prescribed
prescrito
I personally would say that it's
yo personalmente diría que está
prescribed because we're talking about
prescrito porque estamos hablando del
I don't know to what extent it deviates from
no sé yo hasta qué punto se separa de
counting
contabilizar
[Music]
[Música]
time but I would say that it's
el tiempo pero yo diría que está
prescribed
prescrito
in JJ's neighborhood everyone will vote but not what
en el barrio de JJ votarán todos pero no
he would like face crying with laughter I'm afraid
lo que él quisiera cara llorando de risa
vicereina I'm afraid I'm afraid I'm afraid
me temo vireina me temo
the husband of the
me temo me temo el marido de la
slider Yes but that was said but but there is
corredera Sí pero eso se dijo pero pero
confirmation of that that
hay confirmación de eso de que el marido
Carlota's husband  slide was working
de Carlota corredera estaba trabajando
that night on Big Brother because there are
esa noche en gran hermano porque hay
like rumors no and it was said and so on no
como rumores no y se dijo y demás no
but I don't know if that is if that is true or
pero no sé si eso es si eso es verdad o
not Even if the blame for the delay is
no Incluso si la culpa del retraso es
on justice, it is not that I see as far as I
por la justicia no es que vea hasta
understand the things that are
donde yo tengo entendido las cosas que
prescribed, the counting of
se prescriben se pausa de contar el
time is paused at the time of your complaint, for
tiempo en el momento de tu denuncia por
example if this complaint had been
ejemplo si esta denuncia la hubiera
filed in 2021 or 2022
puesto en el 2021 o 2022
then it no longer prescribes Although they have to
pues ahí ya no prescribe Aunque tengan
suspend the trial until there is
que suspender el juicio hasta que haya
a conviction here, no for this,
una condena aquí no para esto no
imagine no Hey, well we set a
imagínate no Oye pues ponemos fecha de
trial date after there is this after there is a
juicio después de que haya este después
sentence but I understand
de que haya sentencia pero yo entiendo
that it is not ten years man Pame for it to
que no son diez años hombre Pame para
be 10 years it has to be so that for it to
que sea un 10 años tiene que ser para
be 10 years for
que para que sean 10 años que prescriba
a crime to prescribe it has to be something like super
un delito tiene que ser algo como súper
serious
grave
but I would say that
pero yo diría que
for abuse it is 30 years for it to
por abuso son 30 años para que se
prescribe Of course but here we are not
prescriba Claro pero aquí no estamos
talking about abuse here we are
hablando de un abuso aquí estamos
talking
hablando
about the omission of Socorro, do you
de la omisión del Socorro
understand? I mean, it's not like she is
me entiende O sea no es como que está
denouncing the abuser she is denouncing
denunciando al abusador está denunciando
the omission of Socorro on the part of the
la omisión de Socorro de por parte de la
of the producer that I already told you is that
de la productora que ya os digo es que a
maybe I'm wrong I don't know if
lo mejor me estoy equivocando No sé si
Paola who was there, give your
por ahí Paola que era que rada su
opinion or someone
opinión o alguien
says Paola there are five bald men there are five bald men I'm
dice Paola son cinco calvos son cinco
going to be
voy a ser
all night what do
toda la noche qué os parece son cinco
you think there are five bald men there are five years of course it is prescribed I think it is prescribed in my opinion it is prescribed one thing is that she hadn't reported José María Then yes she can Yes yes she could report it Because if that Yes takes longer to prescribe
más en prescribir
Araceli based Thank you very much that I
Araceli basada Muchas gracias
also tell you eh I don't know if it's
que también te digo eh No lo sé si es de
José María's in fact it would already be prescribed
José María incluso ya estaría prescrito
if she had reported it now but the fact is that she is
si lo hubiera denunciado ahora pero es
not reporting the abuse she is
que no está denunciando el abuso está
reporting the omission of assistance that is
denunciando la omisión del Socorro ese
a crime that exists prescribed that is
es un delito que exista prescrito
a crime that in my opinion
ese es un delito que en mi opinión sí
is prescribed
está prescrito
I think that this is a bit And with all my
yo creo que esto es un poco Y con todo
love for Carlota Prado but I think
el cariño para Carlota Prado pero creo
this has been a bit
que esto ha sido un poco
to look for the headline
para buscar el titular
And on top of that it is that no she is not reporting
Y encima es que no no está denunciando
with a lawyer, that is, she has filed the complaint
con abogado o sea ha puesto la denuncia
with the civil guard now that one catches her, an
en la guardia civil ahora que la pille
official and such this is not going  to have a
uno oficio y tal esto no va a tener
journey in my opinion eh Paola you
recorrido en mi opinión eh Paola tú
think the same as me you're going to
opinas igual que yo
leave me bald you're
calva me vas a dejar a mí lo estás
explaining it well you agree
explicando bien tú estás de acuerdo
with me no Paola
conmigo no Paola
very little very complicated probability has
muy poca muy complicada probabilidad
already come of this right And on top of that the and on
tiene ya de esto verdad Y encima la y
top of that we are talking that it's not that
encima que estamos hablando que no es
I'm filing a complaint not
que estoy poniendo una querella ni
even the civil guard has fallen to
siquiera se ha caído la guardia civil a
file it This is to make a headline in
ponerla Esto es para sacar un titular en
my opinion this is a
mi opinión esto es una denuncia de
headline complaint as I call it no I think that
titular como yo la llamo no yo creo que
the
la prescripción solo se interrumpió
prescription was only interrupted in the face of those incentivized In the previous procedure of course exactly Eva the prescription of that crime has already passed Look Paola says That's right in my opinion it is also prescribed it was agreed a little late to do it that it could have been done in 2021 or even in 2022 it
hecho en el 2021 o incluso en 2022
could have been done and
podría haberlo hecho y
while they have the preliminary hearings or
mientras que tienen las vistas previas o
whatever and so on then they would have had
lo que sea y demás pues hubiera tenido
this Sentence I
esta Sentencia
know it makes sense that you have to
sé que tiene sentido que tengas que
have the abuse sentence to be able to
tener la sentencia de abuso para poder
report the omission but but it
denunciar la omisión pero pero es que
is prescribed It's that this works I
está prescrito Es que esto funciona así
mean the law is like this no you can't make it up
O sea la ley es así no no te la puedes
you have a procedure and
inventar tú tiene un procedimiento y
you have to respect it whether you like it or
tienes que respetarlo te parezca bien o
not, okay,
mal vale
his previous lawyer already said that he no longer
su anterior abogado Ya dijo que ya no
has a path, no, but it's that no, he doesn't,
tiene recorrido no pero es que no no lo
the producer of Big Brother has been
la productora de gran hermano ha sido
condemned for the way he
condenada por la forma que tuvo de
handled the issue,
gestionar el tema
but Triana, what a beautiful name you have,
pero Triana Qué nombre tan bonito tienes
the other day I was having dinner in the Plaza del
el otro día estuve cenando en la plaza
Alto Sano and I remembered you, a
del alto sano y me acordé de ti Un beso
huge kiss, gorgeous, a huge kiss, 10
enorme guapísima un beso enorme 10
members that just gave a round of applause, the
miembros que acaba de regalar un aplauso
whole chat for Triana,
todo el chat a Triana
a round of applause, the whole chat for our Triana,
un aplauso todo el chat a nuestra Triana
a round of applause, the whole chat for Triana,
un aplauso todo el chat para Triana por
please,
favor
you, you, nobody like you, you, nobody like you, there's
tú tú nadie como tú tú nadie como tú tú
no substitute, Rodrigo, how are you, my
no hay un sustituto Rodrigo Qué tal
friend,
estás amigo
nobody like you, there's no Smile, or already,
nadie como tú tú no hay Smile o ya
very generous, Triana giving away 10
muy generosa Triana regalando 10
members, eh, it would be nice, it would be
miembros eh estaría bien que estaría
nice if you recognized
bien que reconocierais el regalo de
Triana's gift, and every month it won't be the
Triana y cada mes no va a ser la
membership. Hey, let's see if we can go. Hey, we'll
membresía Oye a ver si vamos Oye
reach 2,000 before
llegaremos a los 2000 antes de antes de
the date. Yes, true, that
la fecha Sí verdad
is, before the date. Yes, with leftovers, no, I
o sea antes de la fecha Sí con sobras no
think we can reach 2,000
yo creo que podemos llegar a los 2000
even before summer, no, of  Summer no, let's not get
antes incluso de verano no de verano no
carried away either, summer no,
no nos flipemos tampoco de verano no
summer I was getting carried away, I was getting carried
de verano me veníamos arriba me venimos
away
arriba
talking when he remembers me
hablar cuando se acuerda de mí
Pilar I never remember you I don't have
Pilar de ti nunca me acuerdo no me da
time to miss you I've always missed you
tiempo a echarte de menos siempre te he
Javi Good night You
Javi Buenas noches
can watch the news plural it was
Puedes mirar la noticia del plural la
given by channel 24 horas a little while ago
dio el canal 24 horas hace un ratito
Thanks, handsome sweetheart
Gracias corazón guapetón